A Guide to the Laurance S. Rockefeller photographs, Photo Files, RG 1 FA1128
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Rockefeller, Laurance S. and Family, 1880s - 2004; 9
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S., 1910-2004; 1
    - Portraits (Henderson), circa 1945-1946; Five 2.88 x 3.5 cards with halftone images (Box 40, Folder 588)
      Halftone photo plates (paper) with Henderson portrait of LSR. Used for press release, February 20, 1950, concerning LSR's election to the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation board.
    - Portraits (Karsh), 1979; Black and white 5x7-8x10 prints. (Box 40, Folder 589)
      Yousef Karsh portrait of LSR seated holding small book (Photo Index no. 605).
    - Portraits (Karsh), 1979; Black and white 5x7 prints. Label adhesive has caused slight discoloration damage on the prints. (Box 41, Folder 590)
      Yousef Karsh portrait of LSR seated holding small book. (Same image as in folder 589.) Original and copies (10 items).
    - Portraits (Karsh), 1979; Black and white 8x10 prints. (Box 41, Folder 591)
      Yousef Karsh portrait of LSR seated holding small book. (Same image as in folder 589.) (14 items)
    - Portraits (Karsh), 1979; Color 5x7- 8x10 prints; one negative. (Box 41, Folder 592)
      Yousef Karsh portrait of LSR seated, resting arm on chair, small booklet in one hand. One signed print, mounted on mat board, removed from frame (had been in double frame with Karsh portrait of MFR).
    - Portraits (Karsh), 1979; OVERSIZED Color and black and white prints on 11x14 mat; one 11x14 print. (22 items) (Box O 81)
      Yousef Karsh portrait of LSR seated, resting arm on chair, small booklet in one hand (8 color prints on mat board, plus negative); LSR holding booklet in 2 hands (13 black and white signed prints on photo board; 1 photographic print).
    - Portraits (Karsh), 1979; OVERSIZED black and white 7.5 x 9.5 image in 15 x 18 mat. (Box O 110)
      Yousef Karsh portrait of LSR seated holding booklet in 2 hands, in large mat.
    - Portraits (Koshiba), circa 1912-1930s; OVERSIZED 9 x 12 - 11 x 16 sepia or grey tone images (with portfolio covers); some images on mat boards. (Box O 82)
      LSR age 1 1/2 seated, playing with farm animal toys; LSR as school-aged boy (2 sets of photos; 6 items including duplicates); LSR as young man (3 poses; 7 items). Later photos are duplicates of images in the portfolio volume in box O 83.
    - Portraits (Koshiba), circa 1915-mid 1920s; Grey-tone or black and white prints 6 x 8 - 9 x 11.75; some on mat board. (Box 41, Folder 593)
      Full-length profile portrait of LSR as young child in white ruffled suit examining toy bird (removed from frame). Three portraits of LSR as school-aged boy (and duplicate).
    - Portraits (Koshiba), 1930s; Black and white 8x10 (Box O 83)
      Koshiba Studio portraits of LSR. Two poses (5 items). Housed in fabric portfolio cover.
    - Portraits (Koshiba), 1930s; Black and white 8x10 print. (Box 41, Folder 594)
      Koshiba studio profile portrait of LSR.
    - Portraits (Murray), 1953, late 1980s-1990s; Color 8x10 - 8x12 prints; one 3.5x5 print. (Box 41, Folder 595)
      Albert Murray portrait (finished and unfinished, 1953) (photo no. 5096-5103); plus photo of LSR seated in front of Murray's portrait of him.
    - Portraits (Murray), 1953; Color 9.5 x12 print. (Box O 84)
      Photo of Albert Murray portrait of LSR (background finished, different coloration).
    - Portraits (Newman), circa 1957-1958; Black and white 8x10 prints (Box O 85)
      Arnold Newman portrait of LSR standing at Rockefeller Center desk, rocks used as paperweights. Pose no. 48; multiple copies of print and 1 proof.
    - Portraits (Newman), circa 1957-1958; Black and white 8x10 prints (Box O 85)
      Arnold Newman portraits of LSR (head and shoulders; poses nos. 18, 21, 25, and one unnumbered).
    - Portraits (Newman), circa 1957-1958; Black and white 8x10 prints. (Box O 85)
      Proofs of Arnold Newman photos of LSR. Images numbered 2-59, with some omissions. Prints slightly curled.
    - Portraits (Newman), circa 1957-1958; OVERSIZED Black and white and color prints (16, 4) most mounted on 12.25 x 15 mat boards, most in paper folios. (Box O 84)
      Arnold Newman portraits of LSR: head and shoulders, nos. 21 (6 items), 32 (5 items); seated in his library, no. 44 (3 items); standing at his Rockefeller Center desk, no. 48 (4 items)). Multiple copies, signed prints. Also signed color portrait of LSR seated in his library (pose not numbered; 4 copies, with mats cut to various sizes). See also framed portraits. One print of pose no. 44 removed from frame.
    - Portraits (Newman), circa 1957-1958; OVERSIZED FRAMED Two 11x14 portraits, in frames (approx. 12.25 x 15.25). (Box O 80)
      Framed Arnold Newman portraits of LSR seated in his library (no. 44) and standing at his Rockefeller Center desk (no. 48).
    - Portraits (Sippell), circa 1930; Two black and white prints 6.75 x 9.25 and 8x10. (Box 41, Folder 596)
      Clara E. Sippell portraits of LSR (standing in room by mantle and half profile)
    - Portraits (Sippell), circa 1930; OVERSIZED sepia 7.25 x 8.87 image mounted on 15.5 x 20 paper. Preservation note: Photo is detached from sheet, but signature sheet is still glued to page. (Box O 110)
      Clara E. Sippell portrait of LSR (head and shoulders, seated to the left, facing forward). 7 copies.
    - Portraits (Stage), circa 1928; Sepia 6.75 x 9.75 prints, some in portfolio mats. (Box 41, Folder 597)
      Three portrait poses (and duplicates) of LSR by Mrs. W. Burden Stage, New York. Some prints appear to have proof markings. Photo possibly taken as LSR's Lincoln School senior portrait.
    - Portraits (Stage), 1934; Grey or brown tone and black and white prints, 6x9 - 8.5 x 10.5. Two prints on mat board. (Box 41, Folder 598)
      Portraits (3 poses) of LSR by Mrs. W. Burden Stage. One photo marked on back, "July 5, 1934." Includes 2 signed prints.
    - Portraits (Stage), 1934; OVERSIZED Grey or brown tone prints on 11x14 stock; most in portfolio folders. (Box O 86)
      Portraits (3 poses and duplicates) of LSR by Mrs. W. Burden Stage. Signed prints. 7 items.
    - Portraits (Steinmetz), 1938; Black and white 5x7 prints mounted on 7x10 mats (Box 41, Folder 599)
      Joseph Janney Steinmetz series of portraits of LSR at desk in Rockefeller Center offices. Includes photos nos. 5098-5099.
    - Portraits (Turner), circa 1932; Six sepia prints, 8 x 12, some in portfolio mats. Black and white 5x7-8x10 prints. (Box 41, Folder 600)
      Orren Jack Turner portrait of LSR (Princeton).
    - Portraits (Turner), circa 1932; Four sepia 8x12 prints, with 3 portfolio mats. Black and white 5x7 and 8x10 copy prints. (Box 41, Folder 601)
      Orren Jack Turner portrait of LSR (Princeton). Photo index photo no. 691. (Different pose than in preceding file.)
    - Portraits (Turner), circa 1932; Sepia print 10 x 13.5, in portfolio cover. (Box O 86)
      Orren Jack Turner portrait of LSR (Princeton). (1 item)
    - Portraits (Fortune ), 1962; Black and white 8x10 glossy prints. (Box 41, Folder 602)
      Three portraits of LSR at the Palisades, taken by Marvin Newman for Fortune magazine.
    - Portraits (MSKCC), 1983; Black and white 8x10 prints. (Box 41, Folder 603)
      Head and shoulders portrait of LSR, photograph by Jon Riley (multiple copies). Portrait to be used in MSKCC Annual Report. File includes some correspondence concerning retouching of photo (may refer to a color print?).
    - Portraits (National Geographic Society), 1960s?; OVERSIZED Color 8x11 print glued to 11 x 14.75 mat. (Box O 78)
      LSR in sports coat and tie standing before the Grand Tetons. Photo board stamped copyright National Geographic Society. Undated.
    - Portraits (National Geographic Society), 1976, undated; Black and white 3x3-8x10 (multiple copies); one 5x7 print of other photo. (Box 41, Folder 604)
      Formal head and shoulders portrait photos of LSR: undated portrait taken by Robert S. Oakes (multiple copies); second portrait, photographer unknown, has penciled date 1976.
    - Portraits (Naval), 1942-1944; Black and white prints, 2.75 x 3.5 - 8x10. Dickinson portraits printed on cardboard, plus one Polaroid photo of framed painting. (Box 41, Folder 605)
      Underwood and Underwood portraits of LSR in uniform (2-3 poses); photos of Dickinson portrait painting of LSR in naval uniform, 1944 (one print removed from frame).
    - Portraits (Naval), 1942-1944; OVERSIZED Portraits, ca. 8x10, mounted on 11x14 paper portfolio frames (Box O 87)
      LSR in uniform, formal portraits by Underwood and Underwood, multiple poses. Two images of Dickinson portrait painting, 1944. 17 photos.
    - Portraits (Passport), 1920s-1930s; Black and white prints, 1.75 x 2. copies. (Box 41, Folder 606)
      Undated passport photos taken at various times. Some originally filed in envelope along with passport photos for DR: see additional copies in file for Rockefeller Family: Brothers (Youth).
    - Portraits (NAR Confirmation Hearings), 1974 November 15; Black and white 5x7 and 8x10 prints (multiple copies); 1 negative (Box 42, Folder 607)
      Candid profile portrait of LSR at NAR's vice-presidential confirmation hearings. Second image, by Diana H. Walker, removed from frame.
    - Portraits (Rockefeller Center), 1938, 1950s; Black and white prints, 5x7-8x10. (Box 42, Folder 608)
      Press release about LSR, with Steinmetz photo; LSR at his desk at Rockefeller Center (two shots, one enlargement; see also oversized photos).
    - Portraits (Rockefeller Center), late 1950s; OVERSIZED black and white up to 11x13. (Box O 78)
      Eight shots of LSR in his Rockefeller Center office. No date or photographer attribution (but possibly by Arnold Newman?). Photos printed on board stock.
    - Portraits (Rockefeller Center), circa 1959; OVERSIZED Black and white 11x14 glossy. (Box O 78)
      LSR in front of Time-Life building under construction. Photo by Arnold Newman. Marked D-1. Three copies.
    - Portraits (Rockland Lake), 1969; Color mainly 8x10 prints; 2 negatives (Box 42, Folder 609)
      Informal portraits taken at Rockland Lake State Park, July 1969, for Look Magazine, November 4, 1969 issue. 4 poses. Includes photo no. 5398.
    - Album, 1920-1921; Album (7x11), with photos inserted in pages. Black album pages; captions in chalk are partly effaced. (Box O 88)
      Photos from Western trip (Colorado Springs, Santa Barbara, San Francisco, glacier, Columbia River, horses - including LSR's Nancy, cousin Nelson Aldrich. Includes some captions.
    - Album, 1924-1926 (Box O 89)
      Western trips.
    - Album, 1920s; OVERSIZED leather album 11 x 15 x 2, with grey tone images approximately 7x12. (Box O 90)
      Finely detailed leather album with berry motif, with photos from Western travel (Great Falls at Yellowstone, glacier, bear, Yosemite, Anne Hathaway's cottage, and other unidentified images. Some images are carefully captioned.
    - Negative Albums, 1921-1924; Four small albums of black and white negatives. Album 1: 97 small negatives. Albums 2 - 4: total of 276 larger negatives in 3 albums. (Box O 145)
      Restricted due to preservation concerns. (Album sleeves are brittle).
      Four albums of LSR's photo negatives. Trips to England and France; 1924 Western trip; Seal Harbor, Maine; Ormond Beach, Florida; Pocantico Hills and New York. Albums include captions and identifications. Images include family members, LSR's ponies, Lincoln School friends. Transcribed list of image identifications included in box. For prints of some of these images see LSR's albums in boxes O 89 and O 90; and RG 2, series 1, album 100-0 (box A 6). (We have not checked the negative images against specific albums).
    - Album (Negatives), 1924; Black and white 4x5 negatives of album pages (14 items). (Box 42, Folder 610)
      Copy negatives of captioned photos from LSR's Western Trip albums (images not checked against specific albums). Mainly views of Mesa Verde, Grand Canyon, Yellowstone. Includes negative of LSR's pony Nancy.
    - Birthday, 1990 May 26; OVERSIZED framed photo collage 24 x 30.5 x 1.25. (Box O 136)
      Framed collage of photos of LSR, his family, and activities, created for his 80th birthday. Imprinted on mat: Laurance S. Rockefeller, Happy 80th, With much love from the Cousins and the Fifth Generation.
    - Birthday, 2004 May 26; Ring-bound album (8x9x1.5) of 4x6 color prints. Digital Media: photo CDs. (Box 42, Folder 611)
      Album with photo of LSR on his 94th birthday, along with photos of flower arrangements and gifts he received. Two cds of photo of LSR and cropped photo. One color photocopy of cropped photo of LSR.
    - LSR Birthday, 2004 May 26; Digital: CD-rom. (Box 42, Folder 611)
    - LSR Birthday - Cropped Photo, 2004 May 26; Digital: CD-rom (Box 42, Folder 611)
    - Boating, 1940s-2000; Black and white and color prints, 4x6-5x7 (Box 42, Folder 612)
      LSR on various boats: with captain on unidentified boat, place and date unidentified; with unidentified man, print dated January 2000.
    - Bohemian Grove, 1971; Color 8x10 print (Box 42, Folder 613)
      Group photo of LSR at Camp Mandalay, Bohemian Grove encampment. With identifications.
    - Dogs (Sale), 1983; 2 small albums of 4x6 color prints (Box 42, Folder 614)
      Sale, golden retriever puppy, from litter owned by Robert Wood Johnson IV; delivered to MFR on June 21, 1993.
    - Dogs (Sale and Lama) and Birds, 1983, 2000, Undated; Color 3x5 prints; one 4x6 print; 3 black and white 4x6 prints. (Box 42, Folder 615)
      Photos of Lama (black labrador) and Sale together at Kent House (sent by "Nancy"); LSR with Sale, undated; Parakeets He-He and She-She, given to LSR for his 90th birthday.
    - Grenfell Expedition, 1929; Black and white and color toned prints; negative strips. (Box 42, Folder 616)
      Photos, prints from film, negatives, and contact sheets from Grenfell Expedition, including LSR and NAR. Includes LSR holding puffins. Also includes copy of LSR's certificate of discharge from the Maraval, August 7, 1929. (Includes photo index photos nos. 699 and 721.)
    - Hawaii, 1998 February, undated; Black and white 8x10 print; color 4x6 snapshots mounted on card stock pages. (Box 42, Folder 617)
      Images of LSR at Mauna Kea and in Maui. Also includes portrait of LSR in connection with sale of Mauna Kea to UAL Inc.
    - Horse Scrapbook, circa 1920-1924; OVERSIZED album 13.25 x 10 x 1.5. Black pages, with captions in white chalk. (Box O 91)
      Childhood album of clippings, postcards, and brochures relating to Morgan horses, rodeos, and horses in general. Captioned by LSR. Includes one photo of JDR 3, NAR, and LSR with their ponies, and one image of JDR Jr. on horseback.
    - Institute for Pacific Relations, 1933; Black and white or brown tone, approx. 7.5 x 9.5 prints (Box 42, Folder 618)
      Two group photos (by Associated Screen News Ltd, Banff Springs Hotel). LSR in photo of smaller group (Back row, 2nd from left); not located in photo of larger group.
    - Lincoln School, 1926-1928, undated; Black and white 2x3-8x10 prints (Box 42, Folder 619)
      LSR and friends in plays, in LSR automobile, and yearbook photos. Includes page from photo album.
    - Lincoln School (Reunion), 1985; Two 3.5x5 color prints (Box 42, Folder 620)
      LSR and MFR, plus Samuel Williams, Helen Popper, Louis Halle, Carlton Ogburn, Linda Storrow, Carolyn Jones Williams. At Pauline (Baerwald) Falk's, June 20, 1985. Includes photo no. 5025.
    - Mount Rainier National Park, 1920 July; Sepia tone 8x10 prints. (10 items) (Box 42, Folder 621)
      Rockefeller family (LSR and NAR, plus JDR 3, JDR Jr., and AAR) on glacier in Mount Rainier National Park.
    - Naval Service, 1942-1945, 1963; Black and white 3.5 x 5.5 - 8x10 prints; 2 color polaroids. (Box 42, Folder 622)
      Group photos and candid photos of LSR service with U.S. Navy. Various photos of individuals, some stamped Air Technical Services Command (do not include LSR). Also includes 2 photos of LSR on board aircraft carrier, with description "Chief of Naval Operations." See also LSR: Portraits (Informal and Casual), 1940s-1980s (box 40, folder 578), for photo on same occasion of LSR by plane.
    - Naval Service (Album), circa 1945; Black and white 2.5 x 3.5 prints, glued to album (7x10) pages. Pages are brittle, and have broken at the binding. Pages now enclosed in mylar, within album cover. (Box 43, Folder 623)
      Photograph Album of the Navy Bureau of Aeronautics Procurement Division. Captioned photographs identifying officers (including LSR) and support staff, including names, positions, and some organizational information.
    - Naval Service (Album - Preservation Copies), circa 1945; Photocopies of black and white 2.5 x 3.5 prints, glued to album (7x10) pages. (Box 43, Folder 624)
      Archival copy of the above Photograph Album of the Navy Bureau of Aeronautics Procurement Division.
    - Photographs (from Album), 1921-1924; Black and white 4x6 prints. (Box 43, Folder 625)
      Album duplicates of photographs from LSR's album, 1923-1924 (Large album, # 100-0 (4 items).
    - Photographs (by), 1938-1939, undated; OVERSIZED black and white photos, mostly 9.5 x 13.5, mounted on 16 x 20 heavy mat board. Also includes one color photo. (Box O 111)
      Mounted photographs taken by LSR in Jamaica (Kingston and Montego Bay), and in Jackson Hole, WY. Twelve images, most captioned and dated on back by LSR. One or two images may be later additions. Includes two portrait images of MFR, and other images including her.
    - Photographs (by), 1950s; 3.5x5 black and white photos, some mounted on 6x9 pages. (Box 43, Folder 626)
      Photographs taken by LSR. December street scenes in New York, children with Santa, barber shop interior. Some pages marked Drawer 8 (LSR Photos)
    - Pine Lodge School, (1920-1921); Black and white 8x10 prints (Box 43, Folder 627)
      LSR and JDR 3 with classmates. Identifications on back. (Copies of the framed photograph.) Description on back of image gives 1918-1919 as dates, but LSR attended in 1920-1921.
    - Pine Lodge School, (1920-1921); OVERSIZED 7x9 black and white print in 10.5 x 12.25 mat. (Box O 78)
      Group photo of LSR with JDR 3 and classmates at Pine Lodge. With identifications. Removed from frame. Description on back of image gives 1918-1919 as dates, but LSR attended in 1920-1921.
    - Pony, 1924 (Box 43, Folder 628)
      Duplicate photo of LSR's pony "Nancy in a field at Pocantico, 1924" (from his album no. 226).
    - Princeton University: General, 1928-1932; Mainly 8x10 black and white prints; a few 2x4 prints. (Box 43, Folder 629)
      LSR posing with roommates; in graduation robes before assembly of students. Prank photo of student with pistol and pigeon (Princeton, or possibly Lincoln School). Originals and duplicate copies.
    - Princeton University: Commencement, 1980?; Black and white 6x9 print (Box 43, Folder 630)
      LSR in procession with (Chou Pei-yuan), possibly as Honorary Degree Marshal.
    - Princeton University: Geology Trip, 1930; Black and white 5x7-8x10 prints; 1 negative (Box 43, Folder 631)
      Two group photos, including LSR. Includes photo no. 5235.
    - Princeton University: Reunion, 1967; Black and white 8x10 print and negative; plus 4.25 x7.5 print. (Box 43, Folder 632)
      Class of 1932, 35th Reunion. LSR attended dinner. LSR not found in photo? (photo no. 5236-5682).
    - Princeton University: Reunion, 1982, 1987; OVERSIZED Color 11x14 print. (Box O 78)
      Group photos, Class of 1932: 50th Reunion (LSR not present for photo); 55th Reunion (LSR and MFR in 3rd or 4th row, left).
    - Princeton University: Reunion, 1992; Small album of 3x3 color prints (Box 43, Folder 633)
      Class of 1932, 60th Reunion. LSR, MFR, and unidentified.
    - Princeton University: Reunion, 1992; 2 8x10 color prints (Box 43, Folder 634)
      Class of 1932, 60th Reunion. Group photos including LSR and MFR.
    - Princeton University: Summer Camp, 1930; Black and white 5x7 print and negative. (Box 43, Folder 635)
      Group photo of LSR with campers. Negative marked photo index no. 56.
    - Scrapbook, 1934-1956; Unboxed OVERSIZED album 20.5 x 24.5 x 3, with clippings and black and white photos. Album cover is wrapped in plastic and tissue paper. (Box O 139)
      Oversized album of clippings and photos: includes wedding, Eastern Air Lines and aviation, naval service, Wildlife Conservation Society, International Nickel Company, Dauntless, Family trip to Hollywood (1953), William Beebe, Haile Selassie visit (1954)
    - Scrapbook, 1949-1955; Unboxed OVERSIZED album 20.5 x 24.5 x 3, with clippings and black and white photos. Album cover is wrapped in plastic and tissue paper. (Box O 140)
      Oversized album of clippings and photos: incudes clippings on Rockefeller family and brothers; photos of LSR, WR, and Luis Munoz Marin; opening of Palisades Interstate Park Commission Anthony Wayne Recreation Area, June 1955; picnic or board meeting at Jackson Hole, September 1955; Rockfeller Family group photos; MIT board meeting (?).
    - Winks Biography (Illustrations), 1920-1970s; Black and white and color 3x5-8x10 prints and 4x5 black and white negatives. (Box 43, Folder 636)
      Photos used in Robin Winks's biography of LSR, Catalyst for Conservation. Most of these images are copy photographs; in some cases, original photos have been removed from this file and refiled in the appropriate subject file. Includes negatives.
  - Rockefeller, Laurance S. and Mary French, 1934 - 1990s; 2
    - General, circa 1934; Black and white 35mm print strips, housed in mylar negative pages (8 pages). One 4x5 copy negative. (Box 43, Folder 637)
      Contact print strips, mainly from LSR and MFR's wedding trip to JY Ranch. Camping, hunting, views; haying; rodeo; football game. Several images of MFR.
    - General, 1930s- early 1950s; Black and white 2x2-5x7 prints (Box 43, Folder 638)
      Passport photos; LSR and MFR at summer party; LSR and MFR in casual group photo; profile of LSR and MFR together in Hamburg; in New York; traveling; at unidentified social event (around table).
    - General, late 1930s; Black and white 35mm prints on rolled paper strip, cut into sections and mounted on mylar negative page. Some images partially cracked (at folds). (Box 43, Folder 639)
      Contact prints of LSR and MFR at Kent House with daughter and nurse, circa 1937-1938? Kent House exteriors. (See also Large Album 100-3 for prints of some of these images.) (Cross-reference not verified.) Strips cut from rolled strip.
    - General, 1954-1990s; Color and black and white 3.5x5, 5x7 - 8x10 prints. (Box 43, Folder 640)
      LSR and MFR together: on boat in Caribbean, circa 1954; in Baalbek, Lebanon, 1963; at Kent House, 1979; steering boat; at George Grune/Readers' Digest? Christmas celebration, 1985; Public Meeting Woodstock Town Hall, 1991; Princeton, 1991; U.S.O. luncheon, 1992; by anniversary raintree; unidentified. Includes photos nos. 5075, 5087-5089, 5106, and 5130 (Scott - Porter wedding, 1956).
    - General, 1950s-1990s; Black and white and color, 2x3-5x7 prints; one 3.5 x 9.75 print. (Box 43, Folder 641)
      Informal and candid photos of LSR and MFR at home, on trips, and on various occasions. Includes photos of LSR and MFR standing by portraits of AAR, and of JDR Jr., 1950s; at unidentified airport, circa January 1965. Several undated photos.
    - General, 1970s-1990s; Black and white and color, 3x5-8x10 prints. Includes several duplicates and negatives. (Box 43, Folder 642)